<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>email on anhkhoakz</title>
    <link>https://anhkhoakz.dev/categories/email/</link>
    <description>Recent content in email on anhkhoakz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>object_hurled356@simplelogin.com (anhkhoakz)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>object_hurled356@simplelogin.com (anhkhoakz)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://anhkhoakz.dev/categories/email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There is no privacy email</title>
      <link>https://anhkhoakz.dev/blog/no-privacy-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>object_hurled356@simplelogin.com (anhkhoakz)</author>
      <guid>https://anhkhoakz.dev/blog/no-privacy-email/</guid>
      <description>After reading blogs and watching videos, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize that email lacks inherent privacy and security features. Even if you host a personal OpenBSD email server in an undisclosed nuclear bunker with a crypto domain connected to Tor, your emails still traverse ISP networks and reside on third-party servers.&#xA;While it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to prioritize privacy and move away from mainstream providers like Google, achieving secure communication requires alternatives to traditional email protocols.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>After reading blogs and watching videos, I&rsquo;ve come to realize that email lacks inherent privacy and security features.
Even if you host a personal OpenBSD email server in an undisclosed nuclear bunker with a crypto domain connected to Tor, your emails still traverse ISP networks and reside on third-party servers.</p>
<p>While it&rsquo;s crucial to prioritize privacy and move away from mainstream providers like Google, achieving secure communication requires alternatives to traditional email protocols.
Signal, Matrix, and similar platforms offer better options for long-term privacy and security compared to standard email services like Gmail and Outlook.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s important to acknowledge that trusting any company, regardless of claims about zero trust, encryption, or adherence to privacy laws, carries risks.
Even with end-to-end encryption, companies can potentially compromise your security, making it essential to explore options beyond conventional email.</p>
<p>For enhanced privacy, consider using <a href="https://signal.org/">Signal</a> or exploring alternatives.
However, always exercise caution and, if needed, encrypt your emails using PGP and mail client add-ons like Enigmail.
Remember, the cloud is essentially someone else&rsquo;s computer, emphasizing the need for personal responsibility in securing your communications.</p>
<p>In conclusion, don&rsquo;t blindly trust any email provider&rsquo;s assurances of robust encryption or privacy.
Consider employing Pretty Good Privacy (PGP) for email encryption or opt for messaging apps specifically designed for secure communication, such as Signal or Briar.</p>
<p><a href="https://ssd.eff.org/module/why-metadata-matters">Why Metadata Matters</a>
<a href="https://rightedition.com/2014/05/13/michael-hayden-gleefully-admits-kill-people-based-metadata/">Michael Hayden Gleefully Admits: We Kill People Based On Metadata </a></p>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
